Richard, Mayowa Akinwumi Filmmaker, Film/Video Editor, Cinematographer, Motion Designer

Abuja, Nigeria 09053176084, 09026671616 akinwumirichard41@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Creative, meticulous and dedicated Video Editor with an excellent eye for detail, unparalleled track record of clients satisfaction and a deep passion for film and all things visual, with 4 years + experience in video pre and post production. Proven performer during high pressure situations to meet prescribed deadlines.

Creative Cinematographer with years of comprehensive video production experience. In-depth knowledge of still camera management, editing techniques and location scouting. Cordial and efficient professional commended for enhancing video quality by 80% using effective color capturing techniques. Certified in Cinematography.

Technical Proficiences

High level of proficiency in video editing software particularly **Adobe Premiere Pro, Avid Media composer, Adobe After Effect** and **Cyberlink Power Director**. Also familiar with **Davinci Resolve**

Other Additional skills includes Event coverage, Lighting scenes, Visual Effects, 2D Motion Graphics, Composition understanding, Preparing shots.

Work History

February 2017 - May 2018 **Iszy media, Lagos, Nigeria** Production Assistant Intern

O ctober 2018 -**Ginosko media studio, O gbornoso, O yo state, Nigeria** Video Editor, C inematographer

O ctober 2020 - April 2021 **Capital Power Multimedia Limited, Abuja, Nigeria** Film/Video Editor January 2022 -CycleBreeze R & D Media Lead

Remained up- to- date on current trends and new technology to acquire better images

Adjusted lighting systems and other stage equipment to promote delivery of enjoyable guest experiences

Worked with graphic artists, post-production team members and other specialists to produce captivating and successful content.

Education

- School for the Gifted Gwagwalada, Abuja, Fct, Abuja (2012-2015)
- ➤ Ladoke Akintola University of Technology Ogbomoso, Oyo state (2015-2020) Bachelor of Technology (B.tech) in Computer Engineering

Certification and Award

- ➤ Certified Cinematographer at Capacity development and skill enhancement initiative (CDSEI) in year 2017
- ➤ Awarded Best Under 5 minutes Short film(Dissimulator) at African Smartphone International Film Festival (ASIFF) in year 2019.

Some Completed Projects









- Post-production of six documentaries for Danish Refugee council on integrated protection and livelihood activities that addresses issues facing adolescent girls in Northeast Nigeria
- Post- production of Cordaid Documentary addressing Oil Spill and cleanup in Niger Delta
- Post- production of Environmental Documentary on waste management for WASTE AFRICA and Coca- Cola Foundation

 Post- production of CS-SUNN Success Story Documentary and Training of Staff on the use of video for Advocacy and content generation. 	